Ryan Webber

Computer Science and Business Administration Double Degree

University of Waterloo and Wilfred Laurier University

C: (519) 574-8034 564 Stonebury Cres

H: (519) 883-1689 Waterloo Ontario

E: ryan551024@gmail.com N2K3R1

Career Objectives:

I want to continually grow as a web developer, gain more experience and learn new things. My intention is to continually apply my creative abilities to push boundaries and to never settle for broken conventional norms. I believe in consistent web standards, continual progression, open source software, knowledge sharing, teamwork, and collaboration.

Summary of Skills:

I have very strong skills in:

JavaScript/HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Java, responsive web design, SQL, PHP, Database design, general computer dorkiness, mobile web apps

I have a working knowledge of:

Java persistence API, Object Oriented Programing, Bash, Git, Native app development

I would love to become more familiar with:

Node.js, web design, Backbone.js, Angular.js, Ruby, Python

Work Experience

Canadian Tire Innovations Lab (coop)

March 2013 to September 2013

Title: Web Developer

Description: CTi is an innovations lab set up in Communitech with the goal of infecting Canadian Tire with a new innovative process of project management through short term prototyping in a start-up environment.

Responsibilities: Designing projects from scratch, working through use cases and interface design, database design and implementation, back end and front end design and development, project follow-up, in an extremely team oriented environment

Technologies: JQuery, HTML5/JavaScript, CSS, JQuery mobile, PHP, Java Persistence API, MySQL, Git, Phonegap

Use of time: 30% project planning, 50% and coding development, 20% technology research

Fastenal Co

January 2012 to September 2012

Title: Warehouse Employee

Description: One of Canada's biggest distributing company for fasteners and other assorted mechanical items.

Responsibilities: Worked mostly individually performing repetitive tasks on a performance measured system.

Skills Applied: Independent work, strong work ethic and commitment, hard work working with detail and without errors

Virtek Visions (coop)

January 2011 to June 2011

Title: IT Manager

Description: Virtek makes high precision lasers for accuracy tracing and quality

assurance.

Responsibilities: Imaging computers, organizing audits, employee assistance,

generating sales reports, assorted IT tasks

Technologies: Excel, Batch scripts, C#, Apex

Skills Applied: Teamwork, Leadership roles, official business conduct

Education and Training

- Computer Science (University of Waterloo)
- Business Administration (Wilfrid Laurier University)
- Specialized High Skills Major Secondary School Diploma (Computer Technology)
- Recipient of Arts award for leadership and excellence in physical education
- Developed solutions to coding challenges on Project Euler for personal enjoyment

Community Involvement and Interests

- Founded HTML5 mobile app development team with two graduate developers, who then founded their own company developing apps (Unfortunately, due to school commitments, I could not continue)
- Volunteer and hockey participant Waterloo Minor Hockey
- Former member of Bluevale Collegiate Institute programming team and competed in Dwite Computing Contest
- Enthusiastic athlete (hockey, golf, snowboarding, tennis, ultimate frisbee, baseball, soccer, lacrosse)